matthewjasoncraig.com matt@matthewjasoncraig.com github.com/mattycraig

SUMMARY

Over the course of my professional career, I have obtained an extensive background in front end web development and digital design. I am extremely comfortable working with the leading web development standards of today. This includes: building mobile-first responsive cross-browser compliant websites, utilization of javascript frameworks such as AngularJS for single page web applications, and working with APIs to enhance the dynamic experience for the user. I have a great passion for usability and user experience, and the optimization and performance of websites and web applications. I have been able to touch many different frameworks, tools, technology stacks, and environments which has allowed me to become a versatile front end developer and digital designer.

FORMAL EDUCATION

2008 - 2011 • HUMBER COLLEGE

GRAPHIC DESIGN

 Gained a solid understanding of the process and development of various types of advertising campaigns from conceptual design to completion.

2006 - 2007 • HUMBER COLLEGE

DESIGN FOUNDATIONS

 Solid understanding of design principles. Proficient with human computer interaction, usability testing, and prototyping.

CONTINUED EDUCATION

CODECADEMY.COM

Numerous courses & badges completed on Codecademy

CONFERENCES, MEETUPS & GROUPS

- Numerous conferences and MeetUps attended such as FITC & #devTO
- Active contributor and frequenter of numerous web design and development groups on LinkedIn, Reddit, Google+, and Stack Overflow.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2014 - PRESENT • FRONT END DEVELOPER

SANDBOX ADVERTISING INC.

- Developed numerous campaign microsites for clients such as Molson Coors and H&R Block to deliver immersive single page app experiences created using numerous technology stacks built on top of AngularJS.
- Worked with a diverse team to oversee, plan, and develop larger website rebuilds using a .NET backend combined with an AngularJS front end to drive mobile-friendly responsive and snappy user interfaces that helped drive sales
- Responsible for the implementation and maintaining of custom analytics tracking and A/B testing campaigns for small to large websites and dynamic API driven applications.

2011 - 2014 • CREATIVE DESIGNER & FRONT END DEVELOPER

MOUTH MEDIA INC.

- Responsible for the design and front-end development for mobile first responsive websites, responsive email campaigns and social media campaigns.
- Oversaw project management duties from start to finish for simple websites to complex web applications and e-commerce solutions.
- Designed, developed and implemented custom Wordpress themes while providing training to clients.
- Responsible for client technical support and training for custom built CMS solutions.
- Created and maintained custom front-end development frameworks for numerous types of projects for other team members.

2009 - 2010 • WEB & GRAPHIC DESIGNER

WEBTECH DEZINE INC.

- Worked in-depth with real estate agents and offices from around the Greater Toronto Area to develop branding and personal identity for a strong web & social media presence.
- Worked with a custom CMS to provide themes that fit the brand developed for each agent or office.
- Responsible for providing technical support to agents who had a custom built web template including back-end program support and special requests.

DEVELOPMENT PROFICIENCY

- HTML5, CSS3
- SASS, PostCSS
- AngularJS 1.2 1.5 / AngularJS 2 (beta), Meteor JS
- Javascript: ES2015 + Babel, ¡Query
- PHP, Node.js (MEAN), .NET technology stacks
- Jade templating & markup
- · Gulp & Grunt build systems
- Webpack / Browserify Javascript module bundling
- Javascript Testing (Karma + Chai)
- Responsive mobile first web design & development
- Bootstrap, Material Design front end frameworks
- · Wordpress, Sitecore, Umbraco, CMS Management
- MailChimp, Campaign Commander, Litmus Email Testing
- Browserstack, Spoon.net Browser Testing
- Adobe Target A/B Testing
- Google Analytics / Google Tag Manager
- Vagrant
- AODA compliance / WCAG 2.0
- RESTful apis
- Mobile testing environments: Android 4.0+, iOS 7+
- CPanel & WHM, MySQL & PHPMyAdmin
- · Responsive email campaigns
- Social media design and development

REFERENCES

References are available upon request.

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY

PLATFORMS

- Apple (Mac OSX, iOS 7+)
- Microsoft (Windows 7, 8, 8.1, 10)
- Google (Android 4.0+, Chrome OS)
- Linux (Ubuntu)

SOFTWARE

- Adobe Creative Suite & Cloud (Photoshop, Illustrator)
- Sublime Text 3 / Visual Studio / VSCode
- Transmit/Filezilla, MAMP, Codekit
- Git: Github, Assembla, BitBucket (command line)
- Chrome, Safari, Firefox, Opera, IE 9-11, IE Edge, iOS 7+, Android 4.0+

OTHER PROFICIENCIES

- CPanel & WHM Manager, MySQL & PHPMyAdmin, Computer Diagnostics & Repair, Network & IT Troubleshooting, Microsoft Word / Excel / Powerpoint
- Wordpress & CMS management, implementation, design and development
- E-commerce & web application front-end UX/design and development
- Native mobile specific application user interface design
- Agile project management and business development